# **Samuel Nadar** Senior Front-end Developer

- A-303 sagar residency anand nagar G.B road kasarvadawali, 400615 Thanae, India
- □ nadarsamuel72@gmail.com
- +918286907537
- https://samuel-fs-dev.netlify.app
- github.com/samuEl-FS
- in linkedin.com/in/samuel-nadar-376510111
- **12/05/1993**
- À https://stackoverflow.com/users/14037267/samuel-nadar

#### **About Me**

Experienced Frontend Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, GRAPHQL, JQUERY, State-management libraries like REDUX, MOB-X, UI libraries like BOOTSTRAP, MATERIAL-UI, ANT-DESIGN etc. And hand's on experience in cloud technologies like AWS, GCS etc also have worked on container orchestration frameworks like DOCKER and KUBERNETES. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Engineering - BE focused in Computer Engineering from Mumbai University Mumbai.

### **Professional Experience**

12/2020 – present Mumbai, India

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Privacera Inc. 🛮

Joined Privacera, Inc as a Sofware Engineer and soon was promoted to Senior Software Engineer for my extra-ordinary effort in developing and maintaining the Front-End Application.

- Was a part of a mass upgradation that involved upgrading "React 15 to React 17" with latest Hooks offered in the library. Also used "Webpack" to reduced the bundle size using webpack tree shaking.
- Was part of updating UI library "Bootstrap to Material-UI" also reduced and removed the unwanted code by running some "Babel scripts" that helped in removing some legacy code
- Introduced coding standards and developed generic "React Components" that made development process smoother.
- Involved in decision making call and thread's with the upper management and worked and resolved "Customer Issues" directly.

06/2019 – 12/2020 Mumbai, India

#### **Senior Front-End Developer**

GreyAtom Edutech Pvt. Ltd ☑

- Developed online code-editor for multiple "Programming Languages" with theme mode using "Monaco Editor"
- Optimized the complete Project and updated react-15 to react-16

07/2018 - 06/2019

**Front-End Developer** 

Navi Mumbai, India

eClerx Services Ltd ♂

- Developed "Custom Carousel" with animation using "Vanilla Javascript"
- Developed "Chrome Extension" for raising Pull request using "¡Query,javascript"

12/2017 – 07/2018 Mumbai, India **UI Developer** 

LocoBuzz

Built static webpages using "HTML 5,CSS 3,Javascript,jQuery"

#### **Education**

08/2012 - 05/2017

**Bachelor of Computer Engineering** 

Vasai-Virar, India

Universal College of Engineering Mumbai

CGPA 6.75

08/2010 - 05/2012

Junior College(HSC)

Thane, India

St. John The Baptist High School and Jr. College

60%

05/2010

SSC

Thane, India

Shrimati Gujana English & Hindi High School

77.27%

-		
<b>C</b>		10
<b>3</b> 1	kil	LO

HTML	• • • •	CSS	• • • • •
Javascript	• • • •	React	• • • • •
Material-UI	• • • •	Bootstrap	• • • • •
MOB-X	• • • •	GraphQL	• • • • •
jQuery	• • • •	Redux	••••
MySQL	• • • • •	PostgreSQL	• • • • •
Java	• • • •	Spring Boot	••••
Node Js	• • • • •	Git	••••
RESTful API	• • • •	Ajax	• • • • •
XML	• • • • •	Docker	• • • • •
Kubernetes	• • • • •	Express js	• • • • •

### **Certificates**

- Web Development Masterclass Complete Certificate Course
- React Learn React with Hooks by creating a Roguelike game

## **Awards**

12/12/2021 **ROCKIE OF THE YEAR** 

Privacera inc.

For Performing exceptionally well within the given time frame and was able to pickup

on the project quickly.

29/11/2019 Rockstar Rookie(EOM)

GreyAtom Edutech Pvt. Ltd